A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 1-3254 FA739A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- The study of the educational, health, and social activities of Christian religious bodies in the developing countries: The organization of Christian medical care in Cameroun (Reports 001471), 1965; Vries, Egbert de, 1901-1994; Houtart, Francois (Box 56)
  Church -- Cameroon; Medical care -- Cameroon; Institute of Social Studies (Netherlands)
- Latin American studies and activity in Canada (Reports 001472), 1969; Morrill, J. L. (James Lewis), 1891-1979 (Box 56)
  7 leaves + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Area studies -- Canada; Foreign study -- Canada
- Evaluation of research awards for the development of new concepts and practices of delinquency prevention and control (Reports 001473), 1963; Toby, Jackson (Box 57)
  Title sufficient as abstract. Accompanied by list and description of grants made in the area.
  Office of the Vice President; National Affairs program
  06000266
  Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey
  51 p. + appendix
  Crime -- Illinois -- Chicago (Ill.); Youth projects -- Illinois -- Chicago (Ill.); Rutgers University
- Visit to Escuela de Negocios: Universidad Catolica de Valparaiso, October 1968-March 1969 (Reports 001474), Livingstone, John Leslie (Box 57)
  An overview of all aspects of the university is given.
  Universities and colleges -- Chile; Universidad Católica de Valparaíso
- Ford Foundation report of secondary education mission to Brazil (Reports 001475), 1965; Wilson, O. Meredith, 1909-1998; O'Neill, John J.; Barnes, Melvin; Dunham, E. Alden (Edgar Alden) (Box 57)
  Primary and secondary education & teacher education is reviewed.
  06290324;L63-1029.
  Education, Elementary -- Brazil; Education, Secondary -- Brazil; Teachers -- Training of -- Brazil
- Population matters in Peru (Reports 001476), 1969; Saunders, John, 1930-2012 (Box 57)
  Population studies and programs in Peru are reviewed.
  06590048
  Population -- Study and teaching; Birth control -- Peru; Demography -- Peru; Center for Studies of Population and Development (Peru)
- Center for Studies of Population and Development programs (Reports 001477), 1969; Saunders, John, 1930-2012 (Box 57)
  06500358;06590048.
  Center Of Studies Of Population And Development
  CEPD programs ...
  Birth control -- Peru; Birth control research -- Peru; Population assistance -- Peru; n y Desarrollo.
- I.B.M. in Bedford-Stuyvesant (Reports 001478), 1969; Schrank, Robert, 1917-; Stein, Susan B. (Box 57)
  The IBM experience in Bedford-Stuyvesant is reviewed.
  06900058
  Bedford-Stuyvesant D And S Corporation
  IBM in Bedford-Stuyvesant
  Community development corporations -- New York (State) -- New York; Community development -- New York (State) -- New York; Industrial location -- New York (State) -- New York; Industrialization -- New York (State) -- New York; African Americans -- New York (State); International Business Machines Corporation; Bedford-Stuyvesant Development and Services Corporation
- CONESCAL meeting, 17-28 November 1968 Santiago, Chile (Reports 001479), Miller, Ewing H. (Box 57)
  The desirability of a multidisciplinary team being involved in all areas of educational design is discussed. Various memoranda & letters are attached.
  CONESCAL meeting (Chile)
  School planning -- Venezuela; Campus planning -- Venezuela; Architecture -- Venezuela; Universidad de Oriente (Cumaná, Venezuela)
- Getting more out of the mass media: a modern guide for modern family planning programmes (Reports 001480), 1969; Wilder, Frank (Box 57)
  L69-369
  Birth control; Mass media
- A charter for the Indian Institute of Public Administration in Personnel Management (Reports 001481), 1969; Stahl, O. Glenn (Box 57)
  A program of personnel management at the IIPA is proposed.
  Public administration -- India; Personnel management -- India; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- India; Indian Institute of Public Administration
- Report and recommendations: Peru consultantship August 4-9 (Reports 001482), 1969; Plaxico, James Sam, 1924- (Box 57)
  Possible Ford Foundation assistance to the La Molina National University of Agriculture is discussed.
  Agricultural colleges -- Peru; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Peru; La Molina National University of Agriculture
- The National Family Planning Board, Kingston, Jamaica, May 10-18 (Reports 001483), 1969; Ebanks, G. E. (Box 57)
  Birth control -- Jamaica
- Report on the Institute of Rural Health and Family Planning, Gandhigram (Reports 001484), 1969; Mathews, Betty P.; Krusa, Hans E.; Freymann, Moye, 1925-1996 (Box 57)
  Birth control -- India; Public health -- India
- The teacher and his discipline (Reports 001485), 1969; Parkins, C. Richard (Box 57)
  The requirements of effective teaching are analyzed.
  College teachers; Education, Higher
- The college: possible relationships to the community (Reports 001486), 1969; Parkins, C. Richard (Box 57)
  Universities and colleges
- Production and trade prospects for rice and corn in the 1970's: a Southeast Asia view (Reports 001487), 1969; Abel, Martin E. (Box 57, Box 935, Sheet AG 69-22d)
  Paper presented at the Asia Society-Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group Rural Development Seminar on Implications of Technical Change on Grain Production and Trade in Southeast Asia, East-West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii. Title sufficient as abstract.
  Rice -- Asia, Southeastern; Corn -- Asia, Southeastern; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Asia, Southeastern; International trade
- Relating Indian education more effectively to development, especially to occupational needs: a suggested procedure (Reports 001488), 1969; Staley, Eugene, 1906-1989 (Box 57)
  06890734
  Vocational education -- India
- Diploma in dietetics project: October 1968-March 1969: Baroda University (Reports 001489), Burch, Maxine. (Box 57, Box 936, Sheet EdR 69-5b)
  The project is the development of the curriculum and staff for a post graduate diploma in dietetics to be established in the faculty of home science, Baroda University.
  India Reports;Education and Research
  Dietetics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- India; Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda
- Delhi University program: An interim review (Reports 001490), 1969; Howe, Harold, II (Box 57)
  The overall development of the University of Delhi is discussed.
  06700444
  Academic libraries -- India -- Delhi (India); Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- India -- Delhi (India); Law -- Study and teaching -- India -- Delhi (India); Language and languages -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- India -- Delhi (India); Teacher exchange programs -- India -- Delhi (India); University of Delhi
- Water management: rice production (Reports 001491), 1969; Williams, Donald A., Dr. (Box 57, Box 935, Sheet AG 69-29c)
  Improved water management is vital to major progress in increasing rice production in India.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- India; Rice -- India; Water-supply -- India; Irrigation -- India
- Cost-benefit analysis: new headquarters building (Reports 001492), 1969; Reed, William S. (Box 57)
  Cost effectiveness -- India -- New Delhi (India)
- A programme evaluation system for the family planning program of the Government of India (Reports 001493), 1969; Hjort, Howard W. (Box 57)
  Birth control -- India
- Comments on evaluation of the West Bengal family planning programs, June 9 (Reports 001494), 1969; Freedman, Ronald, 1917-2007 (Box 57)
  Discussion of the need for evaluation units in India to work on the family planning and population problems. Paper focuses on West Bengal.
  07090157
  25 p. -- 28 cm.
  PAPER Conference (1970 Apr. 20-24: Marino, Italy)
  Birth control -- India -- West Bengal (India)
- Training for family planning in India: Design for a breakthrough (Reports 001495), 1969; Mathews, Betty P. (Box 57, Box 936, Sheet FP 69-13e)
- Restructuring of Bombay: Problems and solutions (Reports 001496), 1969; Saini, N. S. (Nayan Singh), 1935- (Box 58)
  A comprehensive plan for the redevelopment of India is presented.
  167 p.
  City planning -- India -- Bombay; Regional planning -- India -- Bombay; Bombay Metropolitan Regional Planning Board (India)
- The Nirodh Marketing Programme: a post-launch retailer survey (Reports 001497), 1969; Mohammed, Pervez S. (Box 58)
  The program was designed to bring through commercials channels to ninety million couples a family planning device-the condom, brand-named Nirodh.
  Contraceptives -- Marketing -- India; Condoms -- India; Nirodh Marketing Program (India)
- The IX Latin American Congress of Sociology: Mexico City, November 1969: unofficial report (Reports 001498), Hernandez, Pedro F.; Latin American Congress of Sociology (9th: 1969: Mexico City, Mexico) (Box 58)
  Seven aspects of sociology were discussed.
  Latin American Congress of Sociology (9th: 1969: Mexico City, Mexico)
  Sociology -- Latin America -- Congresses; Asociación Latinoamericana de Sociología
- Rural education for agricultural development and rural urban transformation (Reports 001499), 1969; Staley, Eugene, 1906-1989 (Box 58)
  Rural extension -- India; Rural development -- India; Education, Rural -- India; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India
- Rural-urban communities in the coastal region of India: Problems and a concept of development (Reports 001500), 1969; Saini, N. S. (Nayan Singh), 1935- (Box 58)
  Paper prepared for the 19th Annual Town and Country Planning Seminar, Trivandrum, November 1969. Planning and development for the rural communities of India's coastal regions are discussed.
  Coasts -- India; Rural development -- India; Urbanization -- India; Regional planning -- India; Community development -- India
- In search of juvenile justice: Gault and its implementation (Reports 001502), 1969; Lefstein, Norman; Teitelbaum, Lee E.; Stapleton, William Vaughan (Box 58)
  Published in slightly altered form in "Law and Society Review," May, 1969. The effect the United States Supreme Court decision, in re Gault has had on juvenile courts and justice is analyzed.
  06400505
  The National Juvenile Court Foundation, Incorporated
  Juvenile courts -- United States; Juvenile delinquents -- United States; Yale Law School; Yale University Law School. Russell Sage Program in Law and Social Science.
- The publishing scene in India: Achievements, problems, prospects (Reports 001503), 1969; Isenberg, Artur (Box 58)
  Sital Primlani Memorial Lecture. Title sufficient as abstract.
  06990561
  Publishers and publishing -- India; Books -- India
- Assignment to the National Institute of Health Administration and Education (NIHAE) (Reports 001504) (FP 69-13b), 1969; Leavell, Hugh Rodman, 1902-1976 (Box 58, Box 936, Sheet FP 69-13b)
  74 p.
  Birth control -- India; Health administration -- India
- The place of the fertilizer input in the package program (Reports 001505), 1969; Ray, Howard E. (Howard Eugene), 1926- (Box 58)
  How fertilizer can be most profitably used by the farmers is discussed.
  31 p. -- 28 cm.
  Fertilizers -- India; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- India; India. Intensive Agricultural District Programme; India. Intensive Agricultural District Programme
- Present position and future prospects for rapid increases in rice yields (Reports 001506), 1968; Johnson, A. A. (Alvin A.), 1910- (Box 58)
  The present agricultural situation in India with emphasis on rice is discussed.
  Rice -- India; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- India; India. Intensive Agricultural District Programme
- Economics courses in Indian universities (Reports 001507), 1967; Arumugam, M., 1939- (Box 58)
  Economics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- India
- The lawyer, developing nations and legal aid: a proposal (Reports 001508), 1969; Berney, Arthur L., 1930- (Box 58)
  Paper submitted to the Bangkok World Conference on World Peace through Law, September 10, 1969. A National Legal Aid Program for India is proposed.
  Lawyers -- India; Legal aid -- India
- World political developments and their implication for public administration (Reports 001509), 1969; Stahl, O. Glenn (Box 58)
  International relations; Politics, Practical
- Observations, conclusions and recommendations concerning the State Planning Project (Reports 001510), 1969; Walinsky, Louis Joseph, 1908-2001 (Box 58)
  Central planning -- India
- Quickening the pace in village improvement: A report on the Intensive Village Development (Stage II) Programme in Raipur District, Madhya Pradesh (Reports 001511), 1969; Shastry, B. D. (Badrinarayan Damodar), 1919- (Box 58, Reel R-9302)
  The intensive village development program (Part of the IADP) in the Raipur district of Madhya Pradesh (India) is evaluated.
  Agriculture -- India -- Madhya Pradesh; Rural development -- India -- Madhya Pradesh; India. Intensive Agricultural District Programme
- Conservation farming in the low rainfall areas (Reports 001512), 1970; Williams, Donald A., Dr. (Box 58, Box 935, Sheet AG 70-8)
  Keynote remarks made at the All-India Seminar on Dryland Farming, New Delhi, India, January 22, 1970. Dryland farming is discussed.
  Dry farming -- India; Irrigation -- India
- Interim comments and suggestions on selected policy items for Irrigation Commission (Reports 001513), 1969; Williams, Donald A., Dr. (Box 58, Box 935, Sheet AG 69-45)
  Irrigation, water management in India is discussed.
  Dry farming -- India; Water-supply -- India; Irrigation -- India; Watersheds -- India
- El Colegio de Mexico: an evaluation (Reports 001514), 1969; Blair, Calvin P.; Silvert, Kalman H. (Box 58)
  The six year history of El Colegio de Mexico since its first Ford Foundation grant is discussed and evaluated.
  Universities and colleges -- Mexico; Curriculum evaluation -- Mexico; Colegio de Mexico
- Visit to Argentina: Instituto Nacional Para el Mejoramiento de la Ensenanza de las Ciencias: (INEC), November 24-29, 1969 (Reports 001515), Fischler, Abraham S. (Box 58)
  Improvement in secondary school science and mathematics is discussed.
  High school teachers -- Argentina; Teachers -- Training of -- Argentina; Science -- Study and teaching -- Argentina; Mathematics -- Study and teaching -- Argentina; Mathematics teachers -- Argentina; Instituto Nacional para el Mejoramiento de la Enseñanza de las Ciencias
- A report to the Ford Foundation on past progress and future plans of the College of Agriculture, Malaysia (Reports 001516), 1969; Hill, F. F. (Forrest Frank) (Box 59)
  06600414
  Michigan State University
  Agricultural colleges -- Malaysia; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Malaysia; Makʼtab Pertanian
- Mass motivation for fertility control: six basic points (Reports 001517), 1969; Wilder, Frank (Box 59)
  Paper presented to the National Conference on Population Policy and Programmes, New Delhi, December 1969. Title sufficient as abstract.
- Cost analysis for alternate development, structures for the Bombay Metropolitan Region, 1971-'91 (Reports 001518), 1969; Lalvani, G. H.; Saini, N. S. (Nayan Singh), 1935- (Box 59)
  City planning -- India -- Bombay; Regional planning -- India -- Bombay; Cost effectiveness -- India -- Bombay; Master plans -- India -- Bombay; Bombay Metropolitan Regional Planning Board (India)
- Improving the handling of grain in Indian wholesale markets: Proposals for testing bulk handling in Mandis (Reports 001519), 1969; Holman, Leo E. (Box 59)
  Grain -- Marketing -- India; Grain -- India
- The concept of vocationalization (Reports 001520), 1969; Staley, Eugene, 1906-1989 (Box 59)
  Various meanings of the term, Vocationalization, are examined to determine which aspect would best fit Indian educational needs.
  Vocational education -- India; Occupational training -- India
- Caribbean textbook survey (Reports 001521), 1969; Caribbean Textbook Survey Team; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica) (Box 59)
  A survey to explore the possibility of developing by regional cooperation the production in the West Indies of reading material at reasonable costs expressly for the primary and secondary schools of the area. (cover)
  Latin America and the Caribbean/Mexico and Central America;Office of the Vice President
  20 p. -- 28 cm.
  Textbooks -- Caribbean Area; Elementary schools -- Caribbean Area; High schools -- Caribbean Area; Regional cooperation -- Caribbean Area; Caribbean Textbook Survey Team; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica); University of the West Indies
- Needed social science research in population and family planning (Reports 001522), 1968; Hill, Reuben; Nag, Moni; Driver, Edwin D. (Box 59)
  L70-160
  144 p.
  Social sciences -- Research -- India; Birth control -- India; Demography -- India
- Organized self-help housing in the United States problems and prospects (Reports 001523), 1964; Margolis, Richard J. (Box 59)
  Using self-help housing to improve the housing situation for the economically disadvantaged is discussed.
  L64-181
  Self-help housing -- United States; Poor -- United States
- The study of contemporary China: re-assessment of a dilemma (Reports 001524), 1958; Boorman, Howard L. (Box 59)
  Reassessment of the study of post-1949 China in the United States.
  05500103
  Support of research on political evolution on modern China.
  13 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Communism -- China; Political science -- Research -- China; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia; Columbia University
- China training and research in the United States: Survey report and recommendations (Reports 001525), 1955; Langer, Paul F. (Paul Fritz), 1915-2006 (Box 59)
  What needs to be done and what has been done in the area of Chinese studies in the United States is surveyed. Appendices list a total review of Ford Foundation action in the field.
  91 p.
  Subsidies -- United States
- Population and family planning Indonesia (Reports 001526), 1968; Perkin, Gordon W.; Ryder, Brooks (Box 59)
  The total picture of Indonesian activities in the population field is given.
  06700564
  Indonesian Planned Parenthood Association (Yayasan PKBI) (Perkumpulan Keluarga Berencana Indonesia)
  Birth control -- Indonesia; Perkumpulan Keluarga Berencana Indonesia
- Discussions on Chile held at various United States government agencies (Reports 001527), 1959; Manitzas, Nita R. (Box 59)
  Various educational, social and industrial-economic aspects of Chile are discussed.
  Education, Higher -- Chile; Public administration -- Chile; Education -- Chile
- Notes of Bethuel M. Webster's trip to England, Denmark and Finland, August 4-September 10, 1964 (Reports 001528), Webster, Bethuel M. (Bethuel Matthew), 1900-1989 (Box 59)
  Visits to institutions concerned with extending aid to developing nations are listed.
  06400116
  The British Institute Of International And Comparative Law
  Economic assistance, European; Universities and colleges -- Europe; Research institutes -- Europe; British Institute of International and Comparative Law. Commonwealth Legal Advisory Service
- Revised draft on young European leaders project (Reports 001529), 1966; Mettger, H. Philip (Box 59, Reel R-9302)
  A discussion of both a short-range and long-range program to identify promising young leaders in various European countries and invite some of them to the United States. Page 10 missing from both fiche & hard copy.
  Exchange of persons programs -- United States; Exchange of persons programs -- Europe
- Migration of scientists and engineers from Latin America and foundation grants to support efforts to moderate the outflow (Reports 001530), 1966; Rao, K. Nagaraja (Krishnappa Nagaraja), 1921- (Box 59)
  Engineers -- Latin America; Emigration and immigration -- Latin America
- Financing graduate education and research in science and engineering in Latin America (Reports 001531), 1967; Rao, K. Nagaraja (Krishnappa Nagaraja), 1921- (Box 59)
  Presented at the first Pan-American Conference on Postgraduate Education in Engineering in Caracas August 19-24, 1967. Title sufficient as abstract.
  Universities and colleges -- Graduate work -- Mexico; Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Mexico; Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Mexico
- Notes on engineering education in Brazil (Reports 001532), 1966; Rao, K. Nagaraja (Krishnappa Nagaraja), 1921- (Box 59)
  Notes for the purpose of 1)serving as a brief report of Mr. Rao's observations of engineering education in Brazil;2)recording sources of information on engineering in Brazil and commenting on gaps in our knowledge of the overall engineering manpower needs
  Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Brazil
- University of Ceara: Industry Extension Project (Reports 001533), 1966; Rao, K. Nagaraja (Krishnappa Nagaraja), 1921- (Box 59)
  Universities cooperating in the small-scale industry development in Northeast Brazil and their industrial extension programs are listed.
  06300481
  Federal University of Ceara
  Manual training -- Brazil; Industrialization -- Brazil; University of Ceara (Brazil)
- A look at science and engineering in Peru revised (Reports 001534), 1968; Corson, Dale R.; Rao, K. Nagaraja (Krishnappa Nagaraja), 1921- (Box 59)
  A paper on Peruvian higher education in science and engineering including the Ford Foundation's programs gives a full account of the programs offered at the National University of Engineering in Peru.
  42 p. -- 28 cm.
  Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Peru; Engineering -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Peru; Curriculum evaluation -- Peru; National University of Engineering (Lima, Peru)
- A study of the relationship between Ford Foundation programs in public education and federal programs administered by the United States Office of Education (Reports 001535), 1969; Ellis, Harlan Reed (Box 59)
  105 p.
  Curriculum planning -- United States; Education and state -- United States; Public schools -- United States; Subsidies -- United States; Vocational education -- United States; Education, Elementary -- United States; Education, Secondary -- United States; United States. Office of Education
- Report on some international programs of American studies (Reports 001536), 1955; Fox, Melvin J. (Box 59)
  International activities of students are discussed, primarily in terms of their relation to the strengthening of American academic resources and to determine the role these activities lay in furthering Ford Foundation goals.
  International programs of American students
  International relations; Exchange of persons programs -- United States; Students, Foreign -- United States; College students -- United States; University of California, Los Angeles; University of California, Berkeley; Stanford University; Experiment in International Living
- Economic change and problems of unemployment 1962? (Reports 001537), Leiserson, Mark Whittlesey (Box 60)
  Report is concerned with unemployment that is not clearly attributed to a deficiency of aggregate demand, but is rather associated with an inability to adjust to changing consumer tastes, industrial relocation, foreign competition, automation and similar
  Unemployment -- United States
- A brief report on observations made in the course of a foreign tour (Reports 001538), 1956; Karve, D. G. (Dattātreya Gōpaḷa), 1898-1967 (Box 60)
  A world tour report is concerned with cooperative businesses;rural finance, extension, and land reform, agricultural economics, T.V.A., and service recruitment, police organization and development planning.
  L58-1130
  Police; Rural extension; Rural cooperatives; Agricultural credit; International interest; Land reform; Agriculture -- Economic aspects; Rural development; Cooperative societies; Economics; Economic development; Tennessee Valley Authority
- Reactions to the report of Dr. Elias S. Awad, June 20 (Reports 001539), 1965; Pella, Milton O. (Box 60)
  A collection of memorandum outlining recommendations for the development of the science faculty at the University of Jordan.